Sonam Gautam

♥ Kanpur Uttar Pradesh☑ gautamsonam011@gmail.com७ 0788 047 17 87

in LinkedIn G GitHub

Professional Summary _____

Dedicated software developer with 2+ years of experience in creating sustainable web applications using Python, FastAPI, Django, and React. Seeking a developer role to apply my Full-Stack Development expertise and commitment to usercentered design in delivering innovative software solutions that improve user experience.

Education

BS GCRG Group of Institute Lucknow, Bachelor of Technology (Computer Science Engineering)

2018 - 2022

Sri JLDBVM Intermediate College Unnao UP, Secondary and Senior Secondary

2016 - 2018

Experience _

Navyalsofteck Solutions Pvt Ltd, Software Developer

• Developed and maintained API (Application Programming Interface), web report and export projects, using the Python, Django, FastAPI and ReactJS delivering high-performing, scalable web applications.

Noida Uttar Pradesh Jan 2024 - Present

- Participated in code reviews, unit testing, and debugging processes to ensure the delivery of high-quality software.
- Mentored 3-5 junior developers, providing guidance on coding standards and best practices, which fostered team collaboration and skill development.

Ibest Works Multiple Pvt Ltd, Software Developer

Delhi

• Played a key role in creating dynamic and responsive web pages using Python, FastAPI, React and Postgres.

Jul 2023 - Dec 2023

• Created a service to provide gradient across VS and VS add-ins, optimizing its performance via caching. Successfully implemented APIs on the front-end for enhanced functionality.

Namrata Universal, Full Stack Developer

Noida Uttar Pradesh Jan 2023 - Jun 2023

- Designed responsive websites using JavaScript, HTML5, CSS and Bootstrap.
- Assisted in the development of a real-time analytics dashboard using Python, Django, which supported data-driven decision-making for clients.

CETPA Infotech Pvt Ltd Noida, Full Stack Web Development with Python

· Designed responsive websites using JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS and Bootstrap.

Noida Uttar Pradesh Jul 2022 – Dec 2022

· Python, Django and SQL.

Projects _

StartUpKhata

StartUpKhata <a>C

- Developed Full-stack Accountant platform using Python, FastAPI, HTML5, CSS, React and Postgres.
- Tools Used: Visual Studio, Postgres and Git/GitHub.
- Features secure user authentication (JWT, React Context API), real-time authentication (useEffect hooks), efficient data fetching (Axios), scalable backend services (FastAPI, React), Postgres for data storage.

• Integration of Razorpay for secure online payments with multiple options.

E-Rasoiya

- Developed Billing Software for outlets and restaurants with online delivery functionality, platforms using FastAPI, React and Postgres.
- Integration of Razorpay for secure online payments with multiple options.

Doctor Appointment and Billing

- Automated appointment scheduling and billing processes, leading to a 30% reduction in administrative workload for medical staff
- Integrated secure online payment options that decreased billing cycle times by 40%, facilitating quicker transactions for patients.
- Developed billing and appointment web application for Doctor platforms using Python, Django, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap and ORM (Object Relational Mapping) query.

Technologies _____

Languages: Python, JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS.

Frameworks: Django, FastAPI, RestAPI and Bootstrap.

Libraries: jQuery, and ReactJS.

Database Technologies: MySQL, Postgres, SQLite, and SQLAlchemy.

Tools: Git/GitHub, VS Code, PyCharm, and Microsoft Visual Studio

Languages: _____

Hindi

English